你并非生而为王 洛基
MOBIUS: You weren't born to be king, Loki.
你的出生造成了痛苦 折磨和死亡
You were born to cause pain and suffering and death.
前情提要
能保护我们免于全面毁灭的 只有时间守护者
RENSLAYER: The Time-Keepers are all that stand between us and full-scale calamity.
-永恒 -常相伴
MOBIUS: For all time.  RENSLAYER: Always.
富兰克林 D 罗斯福高中
为什么把我关在这里？
Why am I locked in here?
你背叛了时间变异管理局
You were disloyal to the TVA.
你在时间守护者的房间里 他们不是真实的
HUNTER B-15: You were in the Time-Keepers' chambers. They weren't real.
-那又能改变什么？ -那改变了一切
-And why does that change anything?  -That changes everything!
你们两个造成的关连事件
MOBIUS: The nexus event the two of you caused,
不管是什么关系 会让这个地方崩溃
whatever that connection is,  can bring this whole place down.
我从来没有经历过 在拉曼迪斯的时候…
This is new for me. Back on Lamentis. . .
如果你相信我 我能帮你
I can help you if you trust me.
我们要寻找的人 就在虚空之外时间的尽头
SYLVIE: The person we're after is beyond The Void at the end of time.
这个东西就是守卫着唯一入口的看门狗
That thing is just their guard dog protecting the only way in.
-那我们怎么绕过这只看门狗？ -我要附身在它身上
-How do we get past the guard dog?  -I'm gonna enchant it.
她很自信
She's pretty confident.
上吧
Go!
干得好 嘀嗒糖
SAM: Way to go, Tic Tac!
就这么出拳
HOPE: That's how you punch.
-瓦坎达万岁 -不 你应该没听说过我
BLACK PANTHER: Wakanda forever! ANT-MAN: You haven't heard of me.
-稍等片刻 -比舞啊 老兄
-Let me put you on hold.  -Dance-off, bro.
-他是我的同事 -我可以打一整天
THOR: A friend from work.  ROGERS: I can do this all day.
-是的 我知道 -我会让你见识到什么叫拼命
-Yeah, I know.  -HANK: I'll show you ferocity.
更高 更强 更快 宝贝
CAPTAIN MARVEL: Higher, further, faster, baby.
我们有绿巨人
LOKI: We have a Hulk.
我们要跳上那艘大飞船离开这里 一起来吗？
KORG: We're gonna jump on that spaceship and get out of here. Wanna come?
我们认为时间是一种单向的运动
MAN: We think of time as a one-way motion.
-这是人类的一小步… -他们怎么能这样
NEIL ARMSTRONG: One small step for man. . . GRETA THUNBERG: How dare they!
我的梦想…
MALALA YOUSAFZAI: My dream. . .
我们为和平的权利而战
NELSON MANDELA: We have fought for the right to experience peace.
光荣的使命
LOKI: Glorious purpose!
受到全世界女性的激励
WOMAN: Motivated by women throughout the world.
-若不是爱的延续 悲伤又为何物？ -我会站起来的
VISION: What is grief,  if not love persevering?
睁开眼吧
MAYA ANGELOU: I will rise. SYLVIE: Open your eyes.
《洛基》
你不阻止我一脚把门踹开吗？
Aren't you gonna tell me not to kick the door in?
这个无所谓吧
It never made a difference.
如果你有意见 就直说
Well, if you think it's a bad idea,  I prefer you to speak your mind.
没有 我没意见
No. Nothing to say.
这倒是头一回
That'll be a first.
你还好吗？
Everything okay?
我还好 就是需要点时间
Yeah. Just need a moment.
好吧
Right.
-只是 你平时… -洛基 闭嘴
-It's just, you normally. . .  -Loki, shut up.
你没出生之前 我就被裁剪过
I was pruned before you even existed.
我这一生都在等待这一刻
I have been waiting for this moment my entire life.
我只是需要点时间冷静一下 好吗？
I just need a second to get my head straight, okay?
当然 没问题
Sure. Of course.
你们好啊
Hey, y'all.
又是你？
SYLVIE: You again?
欢迎来到时间尽头的城堡
Welcome to The Citadel at the End of Time.
来吧
Come on.
恭喜你们
MISS MINUTES: Congratulations.
你们经历了艰难险阻来到这里
Y'all had an awfully long journey to get here.
他很钦佩
He's impressed.
谁很钦佩？
Who's impressed?
遗留之人
He Who Remains.
他是谁？
And who is he?
他缔造了一切 他掌控着一切
He created all and he controls all.
在时间的尽头 只有遗留之人
At the end, it is only He Who Remains.
他想和你们谈个条件
And he wants to offer you a deal.
他一直在进行一些有创意的调整
He's been making a few creative adjustments,
他已经想到了办法 可以让你们重新回到时间线里
and he's worked it out so we can reinsert both of y'all back into the Timeline
同时不会影响其它的事情
in a way that won't disrupt things.
〝不会影响其它的事情〞？
-"Won't disrupt things"?  -MISS MINUTES: Mmm-hmm.
时间变异管理局可以继续它的重要工作
The TVA can keep doin' its vital work
你们也可以选择想要的生活
and y'all can live the lives you've always wanted.
我们想要什么样的生活？
And what have we always wanted?
别跟我兜圈子了 先生
MISS MINUTES: Now,  don't play coy with me, mister.
你是怎么被卷进来的 你心里清楚
You know how you got into this mess.
什么？
What?
纽约之战啊 傻瓜
MISS MINUTES: The Battle of New York, silly.
你和那些道貌岸然的复仇者们的对抗
You versus those self-righteous Avengers.
你想不想赢？
How would you like to win?
而且不止于此
But not just there.
你还可以杀了灭霸
You can kill Thanos.
你想要无限手套吗？归你了
You want the Infinity Gauntlet? Yours.
阿斯加德的王位？没问题
Throne of Asgard? No problem.
那你呢 女士？
What about you, missy?
逃跑了这么多年
All those years on the run.
绝望 孤独
Desperate, alone.
你想不想明天早上醒来 脑海里只有快乐的回忆？
How would you like to wake up tomorrow with just a lifetime of happy memories?
两个洛基在同一个地方
Two Lokis in the same place.
我们两人…
Both of us. . .
一起回到时间线里
together on the Timeline.
这很疯狂 但他能做到
It's crazy, but he could make it work.
这所有的一切
All of it.
一切
Everything.
就像你们一直期盼的那样
Exactly the way you've always wanted.
你们可以一起得到一切
And you can have it all, together.
这不是真的
It's fiction.
现在起我们自己写命运
We write our own destiny now.
随你的便 祝你好运
Oh, sure you do. Good luck with that.
走吧
Come on.
时间变异管理局 正在下载
你好
MISS MINUTES: Hey, there.
-怎么这么长时间？ -抱歉
-What took you so long?  -Sorry.
我先解决了一些问题
Some things had to get worked out,
但我下载了你需要的文件
but I'm downloadin' the files you need now.
这不是我要的
This isn't what I asked for.
我知道 但是他觉得这些更有用
I know, but he thinks this'll be more useful.
谁？
Who?
祝你看得开心
Happy readin'.
遗留之人
LOKI: He Who Remains.
留不了多久了
SYLVIE: Not for much longer.
他真的还活着吗？
Are we sure he's even still alive?
太令人激动了
你们两个 同一个人
. . . same person.
有点不同寻常 但是…
I mean, it's a little unnatural. But. . .
Wow!
令人激动
Wild.
遗留之人
He Who Remains.
她还是这么称呼我吗？
She still calls me that?
有点诡异 是不是？但是…
Creepy, right? But. . .
我挺喜欢的
I like it.
来吧 来吧 咱们去我办公室聊
Come on. Come on, let's talk in my office.
和你们想象的不一样？
Not what you were expecting, hmm?
你就是…一个普通人
You're just. . . a man.
有血有肉的普通人
Mmm. Flesh and blood.
-别告诉我你们很失望 -没有
-Don't tell me I'm a disappointment.  -No.
这样杀掉你更容易了
Just a little bit easier to kill.
进来吧
Come on in.
一杯…
HE WHO REMAINS: One. . .
两杯
Two.
请坐
Please, take a seat.
洛基
Uh, Loki.
Loki.
两份糖
Two sugars.
我说过不要打扰我
-I said I wasn't to be disturbed.
那估计你不想见到我
Well, then you're not gonna be happy to see me.
他回来了
He's back.
如果能有人从虚空活着回来
If anyone was ever gonna make it back from The Void,
我觉得那人肯定是你
I suppose it was gonna be you.
对某些人是绝望虚空 对某些人是小菜一碟
Oh, well, you know, one man's Void is another man's piece of cake.
-那么 你要裁剪掉我吗？ -这主意不错
-So, you're gonna prune me?  -I like that idea.
但我的标准可能比你要稍微高那么一点
But, you know, my standards might be a little bit higher in that area than yours.
-在对待亲密伙伴这件事上 -我很抱歉 莫比乌斯
-You know, with close personal friends.  -I'm sorry, Mobius.
我不能让你阻碍我们的使命
I couldn't let you get in the way of our mission.
使命？
Mission?
时间守护者是假的 我们都是时间犯 还有什么使命？
The Time-Keepers are fake.  We're all Variants. What mission?
这一切不可能毫无意义 这就是为什么我要裁剪掉你
It can't have been for nothing.  That's why I had to prune you.
追捕者D-90 立刻来我办公室
Hunter D-90 to my office, immediately.
抱歉 拉芙娜 你可能要失望了
Yeah. Sorry, Ravonna. That's not gonna work out the way you think it is,
富兰克林 D 罗斯福高中
now that we know your secret.
我们知道你的秘密了
你干了什么？
What did you do?
保持警惕 她就在附近
HUNTER U-92: Stay alert, she's close.
俄亥俄州 弗里蒙特
2018年
Secure the perimeter. I've got her.
包围这里 我找到她了
富兰克林 D 罗斯福高中
投降吧 B-15
Stand down, B-15.
你得听我说
You need to listen to me.
-有你说的时候 -等等
-HUNTER U-92: There'll be time for that.  -Just wait.
这是怎么回事？
What the hell is going on here?
洛斯蕾尔法官
Judge Renslayer.
什么？
What?
你们是谁？你们在我的学校里干什么？
Who are you? And what the hell are you doing in my school?
那不是洛斯蕾尔法官
怎么会这样？
How?
咱们要聊的还多着呢
We have a lot to talk about.
你这一路走来可不容易啊 是不是？
Been a long journey for you, hasn't it?
东躲西藏 艰难困苦
Lot of running, lot of pain.
而你…
你就像是龙背上的跳蚤
You're a flea on the back of a dragon.
就像搭便车一样
In for one hell of a ride.
但是你没有被甩掉
But you did manage to hang on.
我觉得也挺不容易的
Mmm-hmm. I guess that counts for something.
我不知道你是否了解现在的处境
I'm not sure you quite understand the situation.
你输了
You've lost.
我们找到你了
We found you.
当然了
Duh. Of course you did.
手起刀落没打着
-Whoa! A swing and a miss.
我们还要继续这样吗？
So, we're still doing that, hmm?
咱们把话说清楚
Let's get all this out of the way.
好了
Okay.
就在这
Here we go.
你杀不了我 因为
You can't kill me because
我已经知道要发生什么了
I already know what's going to happen.
你看？
See?
我不知道你是否了解现在的处境 你输了 我们找到你了
当然了
这就是小把戏
It's a parlor trick.
好吧
Okay.
你们难道不奇怪 我是怎么在你们动手前逃脱的吗？
Don't you wonder how I'm able to get out of the way just before you kill me?
不奇怪 因为你有时间控制器
No. It's because of that little TemPad you have there.
没错
HE WHO REMAINS: Right.
但是我怎么能提前输入需要的东西
But how do I already have it loaded up with everything I need to know
让你们杀不了我呢？
to keep from being killed by you two?
答案很简单
It's easy.
我无所不知
I know it all.
我洞悉一切
And I've seen it all.
我看到了你们在拉曼迪斯上的所作所为
Everything you guys did on Lamentis, I saw.
我知道时间变异管理局不知道的一切
All the stuff the TVA didn't know about, I knew.
所有的密谋 所有的…
All the scheming, all the. . .
交谈
. . . talking.
你们在湖边的小眼神
That little look by the lake.
还真是柔情似水 感人至深呢
Quite sentimental, very touching stuff,  by the way.
不
No.
不 我们打破了你的游戏规则 所以才能来到这里
No, we broke out of your little game.  That's how we got here.
不对 大错特错
HE WHO REMAINS: No, wrong.
你们来到这里的每一步
Every step you took to get here,
拉曼迪斯也好 虚空也罢
Lamentis, The Void,
是我为你们铺好了路
I paved the road.
你们…
You. . .
你们只是走过来了而已
You just walked down it.
剩下的全都在这里
And I have the rest,  uh, right here.
所有…
Everything that's, uh. . .
即将发生的一切 这是事情发展唯一的可能性
that's going to happen.  There's only one way this can go.
那我们为什么要来这里？
Then why are we here?
不是吧
Oh, come on.
你们知道 没有旅途中自我的蜕变 你们根本到不了终点
You know you can't get to the end until you've been changed by the journey.
这些事情 必须要发生
This stuff, it needs to happen.
所有人都有正确的观念 任务才能完成
To get us all in the right mindset to finish the quest.
-没错 -没错
-Right.  -HE WHO REMAINS: Right.
所以这一切就是个游戏
So, it's all a game.
这一切都是…背后的操控
It's all. . . a manipulation.
你会这么想啊 真有趣
Interesting, that your head would go to that.
希尔维
Sylvie,
你觉得你能相信这个家伙吗？
you think you can trust this guy?
-别听他说的 -〝别听他说的〞
-Don't listen to him.  -"Don't listen to him. "
你觉得你还有能力相信任何人吗？
Do you think you're even capable of trusting anyone at all?
我认为人们应该知道真相
I think people are ready to hear a little truth now.
比如 时间变异管理局是个谎言
You know, like the TVA is a lie.
但是如果这个谎言是必要的呢？
But what if it's a necessary one?
某人创造了时间守护者
Someone created the Time-Keepers.
他们创造了整个地方 他们给予我们目的
They created this whole place.  They gave us all purpose.
我必须相信 他们有理由这么做
I have to believe they had a reason.
不 因为我看到了那些被裁剪的人们 等待他们的恐怖现实
No, because I've seen the horror waiting for people when they get pruned
那一切根本没有任何必要
and there's nothing necessary about that.
你知道如果我们不裁剪时间线 会发生什么吗？
You know what would happen if we didn't prune the Timeline?
-什么？ -混乱 死亡
-MOBIUS: What?  -Chaos. Death.
自由意志？
Free will?
只有一个人能有自由意志 就是掌管这一切的人
Only one person gets free will.  The one in charge.
〝跨越时间的友谊 最后的盟友〞
"Friends across time, allies to the end. "
-闭嘴 -说得多好听啊
-Shut up.  -MOBIUS: That was so beautiful.
然后你就让我去送死 你怎么了？
And then you sent me to die.  What happened to you?
没怎么 莫比乌斯 我一点也没变
Nothing, Mobius. I didn't change.
你没变？你背叛了我
You didn't change? You betrayed me.
不对 是你背叛了我
No, no. You betrayed me!
我为你着想 替你承担风险
I looked out for you,  hung my neck out for you,
然后你的信仰动摇了 就和那些时间犯同流合污了？
and you suffer a crisis of faith and turn to those Variants?
永恒的友谊
Eons of friendship.
因为几个洛基 你就把它丢弃了
And you threw it all away on a couple of Lokis.
不 莫比乌斯 我没有背叛你
No, Mobius. I didn't betray you.
我们不能夺走人们的自由意志 拉芙娜 难道你不明白吗？
We can't take away people's free will,  Ravonna. Do you not see that?
-你在干什么？ -我必须要做的事
-What are you doing?  -What I need to do.
等等 住手
Wait, stop.
也许咱们可以一起把这里变得更好
Look, maybe we can build this into something better together.
抱歉 莫比乌斯
I'm sorry, Mobius.
我不会让你走的
I'm not gonna let you go.
别这样 莫比乌斯
RENSLAYER: Please, Mobius.
即使拿着那个
Even with that. . .
你对我也毫无威胁
you're of no danger to me.
你是这么想的吗？
Is that what you think?
那就试试看吧
Let's see.
对 你说得对
和当时一样
Back here again.
动手吧
Go ahead.
你要去哪？
Where are you gonna go?
去寻找自由意志
In search of free will.
我知道你们从道德上 反对时间变异管理局的所作所为
I understand your moral objections to what the TVA does.
我的方法也有欺骗性
And my methods are deceptive.
但是这个使命是真实的
But the mission, it never was.
没有我 没有时间变异管理局
Without the me, without the TVA. . .
一切都将毁灭
everything burns.
那你在害怕什么？
Then what are you so afraid of?
我自己
Me.
你到底是谁？
And just who are you?
很多人给我起过很多的名字
Oh, I've been dubbed many names by many people.
统治者 征服者
A ruler, a conqueror.
遗留之人 混蛋
He Who Remains, a jerk.
但是…这个名字背后可不简单
But it's. . . it's not as simple as a name.
无数年前 那时还没有时间变异管理局
Eons ago, before the TVA,
一个我自己的变体生活在31世纪的地球
a variant of myself lived on Earth in the 31st century.
他是一名科学家
He was a scientist
他发现在他的世界之上 还有多重宇宙
and he discovered that there were universes stacked on top of his own.
在同一时刻 其它版本的我们也意识到了这一点
At the same time, other versions of us were learning the same thing.
自然而然地 他们就有了交流 此后一段时间里 几方和平共处
Naturally, they made contact.  And for a while, there was peace.
这和平其实只是自我陶醉罢了
Narcissistic, self-congratulatory peace.
〝我喜欢你的鞋〞 〝你的发型真不错〞 〝这鼻子真漂亮〞 〝谢谢你呀〞
"I love your shoes. " "I love your hair. " "Oh, man, nice nose. " "Thanks, man. "
诸如此类
Et cetera.
他们彼此共享技术和知识
They shared technology and knowledge.
这些宇宙之间互相取长补短
Using the best of their universes to improve the others.
但是…
However. . .
并非每个版本的我
not every version of me
想法都如此单纯
was so. . . so pure of heart.
对于某些我自己而言 新世界的唯一意义
To some of us,  new worlds meant only one thing,
就是新的征服目标
new lands to be conquered.
现实之间的和平共处
The peace between realities. . .
演变成了全面爆发的战争
. . . erupted into all-out war,
每个变体都在为自己宇宙的存续而战
each variant fighting to preserve their universe
同时毁灭其它宇宙
and annihilate the others.
宇宙几近末日
女士们先生们 这是一切的末日
. . . ladies and gentlemen,  of everything and everyone.
然后时间守护者就出现了 拯救了所有人
And then the Time-Keepers came along and saved us all.
阿门
Amen
不 不
No.
不是 从这里开始 和教义里就不一样了
Nope, this is where we diverge from the dogma.
最初的变体遇到了一个生物
That first variant encountered a creature
由现实中的悲痛凝结而成
created from all the tears in reality,
能够自我吞噬时间和空间
capable of consuming time and space itself.
这个生物
A creature. . .
你们都知道
you both know.
艾里奥斯
Alioth.
答对了
HE WHO REMAINS: Bingo!
我驾驭了这个野兽的力量 开始对它进行实验
I harnessed the beast's power and began experimenting on it.
我把它变成了武器
I weaponized Alioth
然后我结束了…这场多元宇宙大战
and I ended. . .  I ended the Multiversal War.
把我们的时间线隔离出来以后
Once I isolated our timeline,
我要做的就是管理时间的流动
all I had to do was manage the flow of time
防止出现其它的分支
and prevent any further branches.
因此就有了时间变异管理局
Hence, the TVA.
因此就有了时间守护者和整个高效的官僚体系
Hence, the Time-Keepers and a highly efficient bureaucracy.
因此就有了数个时代的宇宙和平
. . . and ages of cosmic harmony.
因此就有了…
Hence. . .
不客气
you're welcome.
你们是来讨伐恶魔的 对吗？
You came to kill the devil, right?
结果你猜怎么着？
Well, guess what?
我在保护你们的安全
I keep you safe.
如果你们觉得我是邪恶的
And if you think I'm evil, well,
等你们见到我的那些变体 你们就明白了
just wait till you meet my variants.
这就是一场赌局
And that's the gambit.
是要压抑窒息的秩序 还是要毁天灭地的混乱
Stifling order or cataclysmic chaos.
你们也许痛恨独裁者 但是
You may hate the dictator,  but something. . .
如果没有他 可能会更糟糕
. . . far worse is gonna fill that void if you depose of him.
我已经活了上百万次
I've lived a million lifetimes.
我经历了每一种可能性
I've gone through every scenario.
这是唯一的办法
This is the only way.
时间变异管理局
The TVA,
它行之有效
it works.
也许你是个骗子
Or you're a liar.
也许我是个骗子
Or I'm a liar.
所以你就要…
So you just. . .
继续裁剪无辜的时间线？
continue to prune innocent timelines?
Mmm-mmm.
交给你们两个
You two would.
有两个选择 一
There's two options! One. . .
你们杀掉我 毁掉这一切 你们要面对的恶魔就不止一个
you kill me and destroy all this,  so you don't just have one devil,
将会是无数个 或者…
you have an infinite amount. Or. . .
你们两个
you two.
你们两个来掌控这一切
You two run the thing.
你在说谎
You're lying.
为什么你要放弃掌控？
Why would you give up being in control?
哥们…
Buddy. . .
我累了
I'm tired.
而且我也老了
And I'm older.
我比看上去更老
I'm older than I look.
这是个年轻人的游戏 要充满渴望
This game is for the young, the hungry.
我经历了无数种可能性…
I've gone through a lot of scenarios. . .
试图找到合适的接替者
trying to find the right person to take this spot.
结果居然是两个人
It turns out that person came in two.
但是你们两个肯定没问题
But it's definitely you two.
就这样 没有什么谎言了
So, no more lies.
你们杀了我 神圣时间线就会完全失去保护
You kill me and the Sacred Timeline is completely exposed.
结果就是多元宇宙大战
Multiversal War.
或者你们接手 然后回到时间变异管理局 去做仁慈的统治者
Or you take over and return to the TVA as its benevolent rulers.
告诉那里的人他们是谁 还有他们所做的一切的意义
Tell the workforce who they are and why they do what they do.
你把真实的人生视同儿戏
You treated real people's lives like some kind of game.
我不针对任何人 这是最有效的罢了
It's not personal, it's practical.
我觉得被针对了
It was personal to me.
成熟点 成熟点 希尔维
Grow up! Grow up, Sylvie!
杀人犯 伪君子
Murderer! Hypocrite!
我们都不是什么好人
我们都做过可怕的 恐怖的事情
We've all done horrible,  terrible, horrific things.
但是现在 我们 你们
But now, we, you. . .
有机会去合理正当地做那些事
have a chance to do them for a good reason.
我们刚刚越过了…
We just crossed. . .
那道门槛
the threshold.
-Oh.
我说谎了
So, I fibbed.
我刚才说我知道一切会怎么样 我是骗人的
I fibbed earlier when I said I know how everything's going to go. I. . .
我知晓…我曾经知晓一切 到某个点为止的一切
. . . everything up to a certain point,
那个点大概是…
and that point was about. . .
七 八 九 十秒以前的事了
seven, eight, nine, ten seconds ago.
但是现在我什么都不知道了
But now I have no idea.
我不知道接下来会何去何从
No idea how the rest of this is going to go.
我很坦诚
I'm being candid.
所以就这样了？
So, that's it?
就这样了？
That's it?
这就是时间的尽头？
This is what happens at the end of time?
你就这么自由地坐在那 然后…
And now you're just gonna sit there with all that freedom and. . .
让我们决定你的命运？
let us decide your fate?
是的
Yes!
是的 是的 还能有什么坏事呢？
Yes! Yes! What's the worst that can happen?
你们要不然…
You either. . .
接手并继续我毕生的工作
take over and my life's work continues
要不然就一剑捅死我 然后无数个我
or you plunge a blade in my chest and an infinite amount of me. . .
会开始另一场多元宇宙大战 而我…
start another Multiversal War.  And I just. . .
最终还是会回到这里
这就是转世 宝贝
Reincarnation, baby.
不 这就是另一个谎言
No, it's just another lie.
另一种背后的操控
Another manipulation.
没有谎言
Oh. No lie.
没有操控
No manipulation.
Wow.
我喜欢这样
I love this.
我喜欢…这种诚实
I love. . . all this honesty.
感觉就像全新的开始
Feels like a fresh start.
该死…
-Oh, holy. . .  -
-你在干什么？ -等一下
-SYLVIE: What're you doing?  -Hang on a moment.
咱们先谈谈
Let's just talk about it.
咱们来了结这一切 杀了他怎么样？
Well, how about we finish what we started and kill him?
-如果他说的是真的呢？ -那又怎么样？
-What if he's telling the truth?  -So what?
-我相信他 -相信什么？
-I believe him.  -Believe what?
一大群怪人会出现
That a bazillion boogeymen will turn up
就因为我们让人们有了自由意志？
just because we give people free will?
-他是个骗子 洛基 -我也是
-He's a liar, Loki.  -So am I.
我觉得他没有说谎 至少这件事上没有
And I don't think he was lying.  Not about that.
很疯狂是吗？没错 但是也许他说的是真话
Insane? Yes.  But maybe he was telling the truth.
最好尽快 时间线已经开始分支了
Better hurry.  Timeline's already branching.
-所以你有什么建议？ -我们再考虑一下
-So, what are you suggesting?  -That we think about it.
到底要考虑什么？
And what precisely is there to think about?
你没听见他说的话吗？
Weren't you listening to what he was saying?
这就是一场赌局
That's the gambit.
消灭了独裁者 谁来填补空缺？
Remove the dictator and what fills the void?
Ah.
你想要这个王位吗？
You want the throne?
不 不是这样的 不是
No, that's not it. No.
-我不相信你 -希尔维 宇宙是平衡的
-I don't believe you.  -Sylvie, the universe is in the balance,
我们所知的一切都是真的 所有这一切
everything we know to be true. Everything.
我知道时间变异管理局伤害了我们
I know the TVA has hurt us both.
但是如果我们杀了他
But what if by taking him out,
事情可能会变得更糟糕呢？
we risk unleashing something even worse?
我建议的就是咱们再考虑一下
All I'm suggesting is we just take a minute to think about it.
我发自内心向你保证 这和那个王位无关
I promise you from my heart this isn't about a throne.
我是怎么想的才会相信你？
What was I thinking trusting you?
所有这一切都是个骗局吗？
Has this whole thing been a con?
真的吗？
Really?
这就是你对我的看法…
That's what you think of me. . .
经历了这一切以后？
after all this time?
当然 为什么不是？
Sure. Why not?
邪恶的洛基的计划终于得逞了
Evil Loki's master plan comes together.
你从来没有相信过我 是不是？ 这有什么意义？
Well, you never trusted me, did you?  What was the point?
你不明白吗？这比我们的遭遇要更重要
Can't you see?  This is bigger than our experience.
为什么在这事上我们的观点不能一致？
Why aren't we seeing this the same way?
因为你不能相信人…
Because you can't trust. . .
而我不值得被信任
and I can't be trusted.
我觉得咱们陷入僵局了
Then I guess we're in a pickle.
希尔维 等等
Sylvie, wait.
等一下
Wait.
希尔维 希尔维
-Sylvie. Sylvie.  -
也许他在说谎 也许他没有
Maybe he's lying! Maybe he's not.
错误的代价太大了
The cost of getting this wrong is too great.
好吧 动手吧
Fine. Do it.
杀了我 接受你的王位
Kill me. Take your throne.
不
No.
希尔维 住手 住手
Sylvie, stop. Stop.
住手
Stop.
我经历过你的处境
I've been where you are.
我感受过你的感受
I've felt what you feel.
不用问我是怎么知道的
Don't ask me how I know.
我知道的就是…
All I know. . .
我不想伤害你
is I don't wanna hurt you.
我不想要什么王位
I don't want a throne.
我只是…
I just. . .
我只想要你安然无恙
I just want you to be okay.
-
但是我不是你
But I'm not you.
-
太精彩了
HE WHO REMAINS: Incredible.
你不要乞求活下去吗？
Aren't you gonna beg for your life?
我可以那么做
回头见
I'll see you soon.
-
现在没有回头路了
MOBIUS: No turning back now.
谁说要回头了？
Who said anything about turning back?
〝永恒〞
"For all time. "
〝常相伴〞
"Always. "
收到 立刻前往军械库 长官
MAN: Copy. Reporting to the armory, sir.
这一个部分就有63个新的分支？
That's, what, 63 new branches in this unit alone?
他的意思是我们就这么放任不管吗？
Does he want us to just let them all branch?
-这种情况下我们还怎么阻止？ -我们阻止不了
-At this point, how are we gonna stop it?  -We can't!
什么？
What?
你说什么？
What'd you say?
结束了 莫比乌斯
It's done, Mobius.
我们犯了个大错误
We made a terrible mistake.
-什么结束了？ -什么？
-What's done?   What?
我们解放了时间线
We freed the Timeline.
我们在风暴之后找到了他
We found him beyond the storm.
时间尽头的城堡
A Citadel at the End of Time.
他太可怕了 他谋划了一切
He's terrifying. He planned everything.
他洞悉一切 他无所不知
He's seen everything. He knows everything.
这很复杂 好吗？
It's complicated. Okay?
-没错 -但是有人要来了
-Right.  -But someone is coming.
一个非常危险人物的无数个不同的版本
Countless different versions of a very dangerous person.
他们即将开战 我们得做好准备
And they're all set on war.  We need to prepare.
别着急 你是个分析师 对不对？
Take it easy.  You're an analyst, right?
-你是哪个部门的？ -什么？
-What division are you from?  -What?
-你在说什么？ -你是谁？叫什么名字？
-What are you talking about?  -Who are you? What's your name?
立刻派警卫来档案馆
Boots on the ground now. Archives.
你是谁？
Who are you?
根据漫威漫画改编
漫威影业出品
《洛基》
洛基将在第二季中回归
字幕翻译：虫二